robooption.com 2019-07-08

# Privacy policy - RoboMarkets

RoboMarkets not only provides services in business area, but also ensures the privacy and complete security of each of our clients. This policy applies not only to the current customers, but also to past and future clients.

### Who collects the data?

RoboMarkets Ltd, a member of RoboMarkets group, is a European broker regulated by the Cyprus Securities and Exchange Commission (CySEC), license No. 191/13.

The company collects personal, behavioral, and other types of data that you consent to share with us when using all the web-properties of the Company, such as: [https://www.robomarkets.com](https://www.robomarkets.com/), [https://www.copyfx.com](https://www.copyfx.com/), [https://ramm.roboforex.com](https://ramm.roboforex.com/), [https://webtrader.robomarkets.com](https://webtrader.robomarkets.com/), including their language versions. In this case the Client will be informed about this and asked for prior consent.

Any information about your activities collected by us is used only for business purposes and intended to increase the quality of service, timely provide you with information about new services and products of RoboMarkets, thoroughly assess of your financial capabilities and needs, as well as to process transactions.

### What kind of data do we collect?

We may collect, store, and use the following personal data, which includes but not limited to:

 **Identity data:** your first/middle/last name, username or any other identifier created by you when using our services, proof of your identity in a form of a numeric image, date and place of birth, gender, country of residence and citizenship.

 **Contact data:** your address of residence including the proof of this address in a form of a numeric image, your phone number, e-mail address.

 **Professional data:** education level, occupation, employer name, experience in online trading, knowledge about online trading and the risks involved in it, including all the relevant proofs of this data.

 **Financial and Tax data:** annual and monthly income, net worth, TIN and the country of tax residence, bank account number and bank statements, bank cards numbers and the proof of their ownership, electronic wallets details, source of funds.

 **Technical usage data:** your IP address and location, browser type and version, device type and model, operating system and any other data related to the characteristics of the device you're using to access and use our websites.

 **Behavioral data:** all the data related to your behavior on our websites - clicks on links, downloads, scrolls, etc.

 **Marketing data:** consents to receive marketing and advertising materials from us as well as the type of communication channel and the language of the message.

## Cookies policy

Cookies are files containing the information that websites use to register traffic. This information from the website server is temporarily saved on the hard disk of your computer or mobile device when you visit the website for the first time and, subsequently, allows the website to recognize your browser.

RoboMarkets Ltd uses cookies to define what services are the most interesting ones for its clients and measure visitors’ activity on the Company’s websites. Using cookies, we also identify the most requested advertisements and estimate the popularity of resources related to the attracting of the potential clients.

### What types of cookies do we use?

 **Session cookies:** this type of cookies is used only during your session on our website (when you use our website) and is stored only until you close your browser.

 **Analytical cookies:** this type of cookies collects the behavioral information on how you use our website and transfers it to our analytical software where it can be stored up to 6 months. The information stored doesn't contain your name, e-mail address or any other personal information, thus is anonymous. We use it to track users' activity on our web pages, which allows us to provide the seamless user experience across all our platforms and keep track of potential inaccuracies.

 **Promotional cookies:** this type of cookies is used to provide the relevant advertising to any of our website’s visitors at the moment when they are not using one of our platforms. They may include third-party cookies of one or more of our advertising partners.

 **Preferences and functionality cookies:** this type of cookies determines the choices you make while using our website, whether it is the website language or the closing of a pop-up window.

### How to manage cookies preferences

You can delete the cookies placed on your computer when visiting our websites using your browser settings. The instruction of managing cookies in the most popular browsers can be found below:

  * Google Chrome - [https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en)
  * Microsoft Edge - <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy>
  * Mozilla Firefox - <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>
  * Microsoft Internet Explorer - <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>
  * Opera - <https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/privacy/>
  * Apple Safari - <https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US>

Make sure that you fully acknowledge that deleting cookies may affect the functionality you use on our and other websites.

### What do we collect and process your personal data for?

The general document describing the legal basis, on which we process your personal data, can be found on [our website](https://www.robomarkets.com/about/company/documents/) or in a [Client's Members Area](https://my.robomarkets.com/en/profile/documents/): [Terms of Personal Data Processing](https://my.robomarkets.com/files/document/terms_of_personal_data_processing_eu.pdf).

The main reasons and purposes of collecting personal data in accordance with the legislation are described below:

 **Contract obligations:** in order to on-board you as a Client, we have to request and verify your personal information according to our Terms of Business.

 **Legal obligations:** RoboMarkets is a subject to a number of various laws, which apply to financial organizations (e.g. anti-money laundering laws, financial services laws, corporation laws, privacy laws and tax laws). These laws and directives oblige the Company to collect and store personal data requested in their texts.

 **Complaints' enquiries:** to perform an enquiry concerning your complaints, we may use the data you've provided upon enquiry.

 **Data analysis:** we use various tools to gather behavioral and quantitative data about the users of our websites and subscribers to our emails in order to provide them with ultimate user experience and relevant content.

 **Marketing purposes:** if you consent to receive our marketing communication materials, we will use the personal data you've provided to send you information about our products, services, and upcoming events.

 **Legal Notifications:** we are obliged by the Law to advise you of changes to our products, services and/or agreements, therefore we may use your personal data.

The main reasons and purposes of collecting your personal data are described in the document [TERMS OF PERSONAL DATA PROCESSING](https://my.robomarkets.com/files/document/terms_of_personal_data_processing_eu.pdf).

### Who may we disclose your personal data to?

The Company reserves the right to disclose personal data in the required volume and in the above purposes to:

  * Third-party marketing and advertising providers;
  * Third-party services providers;
  * Affiliates and affiliated companies;
  * Governing bodies;
  * Auditors and contractors;
  * Anyone, authorized by you.

Please, be advised that your personal data can never be disclosed to any of third parties unknown to the Company and with which it doesn't have an appropriate agreement.

In any case, the Client will be informed about this and should give prior consent for these activities in accordance with the GDPR.

### Transferring the data outside the EEA

RoboMarkets does not transfer your personal data outside the EEA.

### Your rights regarding your personal data

According to the Law, you have the following rights regarding your personal data we store and process:

1\. The right to be informed about the fact that we're processing your personal data and which data exactly we are processing.

2\. The right of access to your personal data.

3\. The right to rectify your personal data in case it is not accurate or not up-to-date.

4\. The right to erase your personal data from our servers upon your justified request.

5\. The right to restrict processing of your personal data (which does not imply its storage).

6\. The right to data portability. In certain circumstances, you have the right to obtain all your personal data we store in a machine readable format.

7\. The right to object the processing of your personal data.

8\. The right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling if it doesn't intervene in performing the contract between you and RoboMarkets.

In respect of the Client’s rights, the Company informs you that you are able to exercise the above-mentioned rights if this does not contradict the legal requirements in relation to the Prevention of Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Laws, Record Keeping obligations of the Company etc.

### Data Protection Officer

To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints to any data protection matter between you and the Company, please in the first instance contact our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@robomarkets.com](mailto:dpo@robomarkets.com).
